<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<DB>
	<QREC on="1"><A_Type><![CDATA[GW]]></A_Type><UPDATED><![CDATA[Jul 19]]></UPDATED><DEV_COMMENT dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[English Edited by Liza Li 07/19/2011]]></DEV_COMMENT><OL_Title dir="ltr" esbox="1"><![CDATA[Dialog on Islam and the West (2)]]></OL_Title><LO_SHORT_DESCRIPT dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[An interview about Islam and Western media.]]></LO_SHORT_DESCRIPT><QUARTER><![CDATA[q4]]></QUARTER><TOPICs2 dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[]]></TOPICs2><KEY_WORDS dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[innocent people, terrorism, Islam, Western societies, media]]></KEY_WORDS><LANGUAGE><![CDATA[Arabic]]></LANGUAGE><THEME><![CDATA[Fiesta Blue]]></THEME><YEAR><![CDATA[2011]]></YEAR><FL_Title dir="rtl"><![CDATA[حوار حول الاسلام و الغرب (جزء 2)]]></FL_Title><XL_Title dir="ltr"><![CDATA[Dialog on Islam and the West (Part 2)]]></XL_Title><MODALITY><![CDATA[Listening]]></MODALITY><LEVEL><![CDATA[3]]></LEVEL><TOPIC><![CDATA[Security]]></TOPIC><TOPICs1><![CDATA[Security Issues (e.g. terrorism, trafficking)]]></TOPICs1><RES_TYPE><![CDATA[text]]></RES_TYPE><RES_TYPE cked="true"><![CDATA[audio]]></RES_TYPE><RES_TYPE><![CDATA[video]]></RES_TYPE><TEXT_MOD><![CDATA[orientational]]></TEXT_MOD><TEXT_MOD cked="true"><![CDATA[instructive]]></TEXT_MOD><TEXT_MOD cked="true"><![CDATA[evaluative]]></TEXT_MOD><TEXT_MOD><![CDATA[projective]]></TEXT_MOD><COMP_BROWSER cked="true"><![CDATA[ie60]]></COMP_BROWSER><COMP_BROWSER cked="true"><![CDATA[nn70]]></COMP_BROWSER><OBJECTIVES><![CDATA[]]></OBJECTIVES></QREC><QREC on="1"><A_Type><![CDATA[CO]]></A_Type><UPDATED><![CDATA[Jul 19]]></UPDATED><DEV_COMMENT dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[OK]]></DEV_COMMENT><CO_ParaFL dir="rtl" esbox="0"><![CDATA[<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>الضيف:</FONT></STRONG> لا يختلف يعني إنسان مع آخر على انه قتل الأبرياء والمدنيين دون مبرر ولا ذنب، هذا شيء مرفوض سواء كان الإنسان هذا مسلم أو غير مسلم. لكن هنا سؤالان إذا كان تفجير سفارة أو مدمرة أو سيارة مفخخة سمه تطرف, إرهاب, تعصب, فماذا نسمي احتلال بلاد بأكملها؟ فلسطين محتلة, العراق محتل, أفغانستان محتلة والقصف والتدمير يومي في هذه البلاد. ثانياً لماذا نلوم أشخاص يعني ل..لسبب أو لآخر تطرفوا بسبب اعتقال إما والده أو أخوه أو أخته&nbsp; أو كذا ولا نلوم دول وحكومات كاملة تقوم بهذه الأعمال ليل نهار تعدم وتحاكم وتسجن بسبب الاشتباه كله اشتباه ب..</P>
<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>المذيع:</FONT></STRONG> طيب سيد سيد رافع</P>
<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>الضيف:</FONT></STRONG> أو كذا, نعم</P>
<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>المذيع:</FONT></STRONG> ليس كل هؤلاء يعني يمكن أن نقول عنهم أنهم يعنوا, يعني ان نضفي عليهم صبغة البراءة لا بد أن هناك عوامل </P>
<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>الضيف:</FONT></STRONG> اكيد اكيد نعم نعم.. نعم, أكمل عفواً</P>
<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>المذيع:</FONT></STRONG> وبالتالي المجهود ربما يجب أن يُبذل في المعسكر الإسلامي.</P>
<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>الضيف:</FONT></STRONG> صحيح. كلامك صحيح يا أخي لو كان المعسكر الإسلامي معسكر متوحد في وجهة النظر على الأقل, الآن اغلب المعسكر الإسلامي وخصوصا (الرسمي), يسير في اتجاه التيار المعادي للإسلام يعني يدين فقط هذه الأشياء الجزئيات البسيطة ولا يتكلم أي شيء عن المعاني الأخرى للإسلام.</P>
<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>الضيف:</FONT></STRONG> أصبحت الصورة التي تُقدم عن الإسلام هي مجموعة أشخاص أو أفراد فين في العراق و في أفغانستان وكأنه هذا هو صار الإسلام. هذا ليس صحيح. ال ال.. المسئول عن تصحيح صورة الإسلام هي الجهات الإعلامية الرسمية وليس الأفراد وليست المنظمات التي لا حول لها ولا قوة. لم يستطع الآن أن يظهر في الإعلام, كما يُمجِد حاكم أو يُمجِد فعل معين أو يُمجِد انجاز أن يُمجِد يعني تاريخ الإسلام في الأندلس أو تاريخ الإسلام في فلسطين أو تاريخ الإسلام في الهند وفي آسيا. لا احد يستطيع. المسؤولية ليست مسؤوليتي أنا كشخص, أنا ممكن اعمل مع اللي بجواري لكن كم يكن كثير مقابل إعلام دولة كاملة أو إعلام عدة دول. فالمسؤولية الصحيح لكن يجب أن تتولى الدول وبإنصاف بإنصاف أن تدافع عن صورة الإسلام في الغرب حتى يعرفون الغربيين الصورة الحقيقية غير الصورة لأحداث سبتمبر وصورة السيارات المفخخة هذه صورة لا تشكل يعني أي شيء من الإسلام. </P>]]></CO_ParaFL><CO_ParaXL dir="ltr" esbox="1"><![CDATA[<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>Guest:</FONT></STRONG> No one can disagree that killing innocent people and civilians without justification or cause is <STRIKE>something</STRIKE> rejected by Muslims and non-Muslims. But there are two questions: <FONT style="BACKGROUND-COLOR: #ffff00">First,</FONT> if blowing up a car, destroying, or booby trapping a car is called extremism, terrorism, <FONT style="BACKGROUND-COLOR: #ffff00">and</FONT> bigotry, then what do we call the occupation of an entire country? Palestine is occupied, Iraq is occupied, Afghanistan is occupied, and bombing and destruction occur<FONT style="BACKGROUND-COLOR: #ffff00">s </FONT>on a daily basis in this [Iraq] country. Second, why do we blame people who for one reason or another resorted to extremism due to the detention of their father, brother, <FONT style="BACKGROUND-COLOR: #ffff00">and </FONT>sister, while we do not blame entire countries and governments that do this night and day? They put people to death, try <STRIKE>and</STRIKE> <FONT style="BACKGROUND-COLOR: #ffff00">to</FONT> detain them on suspicion <FONT style="BACKGROUND-COLOR: #ffff00">alone</FONT>, it is all suspicion of… </P>
<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>Anchor:</FONT></STRONG> OK, Mr. Mr. Rafi’ </P>
<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>Guest:</FONT></STRONG> Or that, yes. </P>
<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>Anchor:</FONT></STRONG> We cannot say that all those, we cannot say they are all innocent; there must be factors. </P>
<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>Guest:</FONT></STRONG> Certainly, certainly. Yes yes… yes, continue. Excuse me. </P>
<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>Anchor:</FONT></STRONG> <STRIKE>And therefore</STRIKE> <FONT style="BACKGROUND-COLOR: #ffff00">Therefore,</FONT> the effort should probably be exerted in an Islamic camp. </P>
<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>Guest:</FONT></STRONG> True. What you are saying is true, my brother. If the Islamic camp was a unified camp in its point of view at least. Nowadays, most of the Islamic camp, especially the (official), is going in the direction of anti-Islam; it only condemns these minor parts and does not say anything about the other meanings of Islam. </P>
<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>Guest:</FONT></STRONG> The image given about Islam has become a group of people or individuals in Iraq and Afghanistan, as if that is what Islam has become. That is not true. The party in charge of correcting the image of Islam is the official media parties and not individuals and organizations that have no power. The media has not been able to glorify—like the glorification of a ruler or the glorification of a certain event or the glorification of an accomplishment—the history of Islam in Al Andalus or the history of Islam in Palestine or the history of Islam in India and in Asia. No one can. The responsibility is not mine as an individual. I can work with the people around me but it is not much in the face of the media of an entire nation or the media of several countries. The true responsibility must be undertaken by countries on an equal basis; they must defend the image of Islam in the West, so that Westerners can know the true image, other than the image of the September events and the image of booby-trapped cars. This image does not represent any part of Islam. </P>]]></CO_ParaXL><AUD_STIMULUS><![CDATA[ad_sec209_Source.mp3]]></AUD_STIMULUS><AUD_STIMULUS><![CDATA[SELECT]]></AUD_STIMULUS><VIDEO_CLIP><![CDATA[No Video File]]></VIDEO_CLIP><MODALITY><![CDATA[Audio]]></MODALITY><OBJECTIVES><![CDATA[]]></OBJECTIVES></QREC><QREC on="1"><A_Type><![CDATA[OP]]></A_Type><UPDATED><![CDATA[Jul 19]]></UPDATED><DEV_COMMENT dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[OK]]></DEV_COMMENT></QREC><QREC on="1"><A_Type><![CDATA[GG]]></A_Type><UPDATED><![CDATA[Jul 19]]></UPDATED><DEV_COMMENT dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[OK]]></DEV_COMMENT><GlosLeft dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[killing innocent people]]></GlosLeft><GlosRight dir="rtl" esbox="0"><![CDATA[قتل الأبرياء]]></GlosRight><GlosLeft dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[without justification]]></GlosLeft><GlosRight dir="rtl" esbox="0"><![CDATA[دون مبرر]]></GlosRight><GlosLeft dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[blowing up a car]]></GlosLeft><GlosRight dir="rtl" esbox="0"><![CDATA[سيارة مفخخة]]></GlosRight><GlosLeft dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[detention]]></GlosLeft><GlosRight dir="rtl" esbox="0"><![CDATA[اعتقال]]></GlosRight><GlosLeft dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[suspicion]]></GlosLeft><GlosRight dir="rtl" esbox="0"><![CDATA[الاشتباه]]></GlosRight><GlosLeft dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[Islamic camp]]></GlosLeft><GlosRight dir="rtl" esbox="0"><![CDATA[المعسكر الإسلامي]]></GlosRight><GlosLeft dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[direction of anti-Islam]]></GlosLeft><GlosRight dir="rtl" esbox="0"><![CDATA[التيار المعادي للإسلام]]></GlosRight><GlosLeft dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[minor parts]]></GlosLeft><GlosRight dir="rtl" esbox="0"><![CDATA[الجزئيات البسيطة]]></GlosRight><GlosLeft dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[official media parties]]></GlosLeft><GlosRight dir="rtl" esbox="0"><![CDATA[الجهات الإعلامية الرسمية]]></GlosRight><GlosLeft dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[fairly]]></GlosLeft><GlosRight dir="rtl" esbox="0"><![CDATA[بإنصاف]]></GlosRight><GlosLeft dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[September events]]></GlosLeft><GlosRight dir="rtl" esbox="0"><![CDATA[لأحداث سبتمبر]]></GlosRight><AUD_STIMULUS><![CDATA[SELECT]]></AUD_STIMULUS><AUD_STIMULUS><![CDATA[SELECT]]></AUD_STIMULUS><AUD_STIMULUS><![CDATA[SELECT]]></AUD_STIMULUS><AUD_STIMULUS><![CDATA[SELECT]]></AUD_STIMULUS><AUD_STIMULUS><![CDATA[SELECT]]></AUD_STIMULUS><AUD_STIMULUS><![CDATA[SELECT]]></AUD_STIMULUS><AUD_STIMULUS><![CDATA[SELECT]]></AUD_STIMULUS><AUD_STIMULUS><![CDATA[SELECT]]></AUD_STIMULUS><AUD_STIMULUS><![CDATA[SELECT]]></AUD_STIMULUS><AUD_STIMULUS><![CDATA[SELECT]]></AUD_STIMULUS><AUD_STIMULUS><![CDATA[SELECT]]></AUD_STIMULUS></QREC><QREC on="1"><A_Type><![CDATA[IP]]></A_Type><UPDATED><![CDATA[Jul 19]]></UPDATED><DEV_COMMENT dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[OK]]></DEV_COMMENT><FEATURE dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[components of an argument]]></FEATURE><OBJECTIVES dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[Understand the main idea and details of a conversation on Islam illustrating an argument while analyzing the components of that argument.]]></OBJECTIVES><COMPETENCE><![CDATA[Discourse]]></COMPETENCE><PUBLICATION dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[www.scola.org]]></PUBLICATION><YEAR dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[2011]]></YEAR><AUTHOR dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[]]></AUTHOR><DEVELOPER dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[Kamaleddine Tabine]]></DEVELOPER><TIME_OF_TASK><![CDATA[08:2 hours]]></TIME_OF_TASK></QREC><QREC on="1"><A_Type><![CDATA[RP]]></A_Type><UPDATED><![CDATA[Jul 19]]></UPDATED><DEV_COMMENT dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[OK]]></DEV_COMMENT><STIMULUS dir="rtl" esbox="0"><![CDATA[المسلمون في ألمانيا.. جهودٌ لتحسين صورة الإسلام]]></STIMULUS><RESPONSE dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[http://www.alukah.net/Sharia/0/1343/]]></RESPONSE><AID dir="ltr" esbox="1"><![CDATA[An article discussing Muslim's effort to improve their image in Germany.]]></AID><STIMULUS dir="rtl" esbox="0"><![CDATA[حوار حول الاسلام و الغرب (1)]]></STIMULUS><RESPONSE dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[http://gloss.dliflc.edu/products/gloss/ad_sec208/default.html]]></RESPONSE><AID dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[Website that will take you to the lesson (Part1).]]></AID></QREC><QREC on="1"><A_Type><![CDATA[LGP]]></A_Type><UPDATED><![CDATA[Jul 19]]></UPDATED><DEV_COMMENT dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[OK]]></DEV_COMMENT><ACTY_DESCRIPTION dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[Recall topic and details of the previous lesson part one.]]></ACTY_DESCRIPTION><POP_UP dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[]]></POP_UP><NOTE dir="ltr" esbox="1"><![CDATA[<P align=center><STRONG><U dir=rtl><STRONG><U></U></STRONG><IMG border=0 hspace=3 alt="شرطي أمام مسجد فرنسي" vspace=3 align=baseline src="Images/ad_sec208_islam3.gif" _src="Images/ad_sec208_islam3.gif"></P>
<P align=right>هذا الدرس يُكَّمل الدرس السابق:</U></STRONG></P>
<P dir=rtl align=right><STRONG>"حوار حول الاسلام و الغرب (1)"</STRONG> </P>
<P dir=ltr align=left>This lesson completes the previous lesson: <EM>"Dialog on Islam and the West (Part 1)."</EM></P>
<P dir=ltr align=left>You can go to <STRONG>Resources </STRONG>if you would like to review and go through this lesson </P>This lesson examines the second part of the interview of lesson (Part 1). It is highly recommended that you complete part 1 before part 2.]]></NOTE><FL_INST dir="rtl" esbox="0"><![CDATA[استمع الى مقطع يُلخص مضمون الجزء الأول من هذا الدرس ثم أجب على السؤالين التالين.&nbsp;&nbsp;]]></FL_INST><XL_INST dir="ltr" esbox="1"><![CDATA[Listen to an audio segment summarizing the content of the lesson (Part 1). Click on <STRONG>Guidelines</STRONG> first to access the questions and then write your answers in the space provided.]]></XL_INST><PREP_TEXT dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[]]></PREP_TEXT><QText dir="rtl" esbox="0"><![CDATA[<P align=right><STRONG dir=rtl><FONT dir=rtl color=#0000ff>المذيع:</FONT> الصورة التي يحملها أغلب الأوروبيين عن المجتمعات الإسلامية سلبية إلى حدٍ كبير. نحو ثلاثة أرباع المشاركين في الدراسة ردّوا بأن الإسلام يعني بالنسبة لهم قمع المرأة والتطرف والإرهاب.</STRONG></P>
<P align=right><STRONG dir=rtl><FONT color=#0000ff>الضيف:</FONT> الإسلام, لا شك هو دين الله سبحانه وتعالى الذي ختم به الأديان والرسالات. والمشكلة الآن هي ليست يعني هي قناعة الآخرين بالإسلام, المشكلة هي الصورة التي يحاول الإعلام المعادي للإسلام تشكيلها وتصوير الإسلام بها. </STRONG></P>]]></QText><AID dir="ltr" esbox="1"><![CDATA[<P>As you may recall, the anchor and his guest are discussing the results of a European survey on Islam in Europe. In this preliminary activity, listen carefully to the two main statements made by the anchor and the guest, then answer the following questions to get a summary of the first part of this lesson:</P>
<OL>
<LI><STRONG>ما هي نتائج الاستطلاع حول الاسلام في أوروبا؟</STRONG>&nbsp; (<EM>What do the survey results tell us about opinions on Islam in Europe?</EM>) 
<LI><STRONG>كيف يُفسر ضيف البرنامج النظرة المُعادية للاسلام في أوروبا؟</STRONG> (<EM>How does the guest explain Europeans' negative view on Islam?</EM>)</LI></OL>]]></AID><STIMULUS dir="ltr" esbox="1"><![CDATA[1. The anchor states that, according to the poll, 75% of Europeans associate Islam with&nbsp; oppression of women, extremism, and terrorism.]]></STIMULUS><FB dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[1. This is the first key idea in the lesson (Part 1). First, the anchor talks about<STRONG> استطلاع</STRONG> <STRONG>أوروبي</STRONG> <EM>(European survey)</EM>, and then he provides the results that show that the majority of Europeans have a<STRONG> نظرة سلبية</STRONG> <EM>(negative view)</EM> towards Islam. The anchor also lists the three terms to which Europeans attribute to Islam, which are<STRONG> قمع المرأة</STRONG> (oppression of women),<STRONG> التطرف</STRONG> <EM>(extremism)</EM> and<STRONG> الإرهاب</STRONG> <EM>(terrorism).&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </EM>
<P dir=rtl align=right><STRONG>الإسلام يعني بالنسبة لهم <FONT color=#0000ff>قمع المرأة والتطرف والإرهاب </FONT></STRONG></P>
<P></P>]]></FB><STIMULUS dir="ltr" esbox="1"><![CDATA[2. Here, the guest believes that growing negative views of Islam are related to the anti-Islamic images in the Western media.]]></STIMULUS><FB dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[2. This is the second main idea in this first part of this lesson. The guest mentions that <STRONG>الاعلام المعادي للإسلام</STRONG> <EM>(anti-Islam media)</EM> is mainly responsible for spreading negative views about Islam in Europe.&nbsp;&nbsp; 
<P dir=rtl align=right><STRONG>المشكلة هي الصورة التي يحاول <FONT color=#0000ff>الإعلام المعادي للإسلام</FONT> تشكيلها وتصوير الإسلام بها </STRONG></P>]]></FB><AUD_FB><![CDATA[1.mp3]]></AUD_FB><AUD_FB><![CDATA[2.mp3]]></AUD_FB><AUD_STIMULUS><![CDATA[3.mp3]]></AUD_STIMULUS><AUD_STIMULUS><![CDATA[SELECT]]></AUD_STIMULUS><PREP_AUD><![CDATA[SELECT]]></PREP_AUD></QREC><QREC on="1"><A_Type><![CDATA[LBS]]></A_Type><UPDATED><![CDATA[Jul 19]]></UPDATED><DEV_COMMENT dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[OK]]></DEV_COMMENT><ACTY_DESCRIPTION dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[Identify the main ideas and supporting details in the audio passage.]]></ACTY_DESCRIPTION><POP_UP dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[]]></POP_UP><NOTE dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[In this part of the audio conversation, the anchor is resuming his comment about the issue of Islam and the West. You will start listening to the second part of the conversation which is not featured in Part I of the lesson.]]></NOTE><FL_INST dir="rtl" esbox="0"><![CDATA[استمع إلى النصوص الآتية على حدة تم اكتب الإجابة في الحقل المخصص لذلك. </P>]]></FL_INST><XL_INST dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[Listen to the following segments separately, and write your answers in the spaces provided.]]></XL_INST><PREP_TEXT dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[]]></PREP_TEXT><AID><![CDATA[wholeAudio]]></AID><NUM_Q><![CDATA[All]]></NUM_Q><STIMULUS dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[]]></STIMULUS><AUD_STIMULUS><![CDATA[ad_sec209_activity_2_part1.mp3]]></AUD_STIMULUS><RESPONSE dir="ltr" esbox="0" segNo="0"><![CDATA[<P align=right><STRONG dir=rtl><FONT size=2>ما رأي ضيف البرنامج في قتل المدنيين؟ </FONT></STRONG></P>
<P dir=ltr align=left><EM><FONT size=2>What is the guest's opinion on killing civilians? </FONT></EM></P>]]></RESPONSE><FB dir="ltr" esbox="1" segNo="0"><![CDATA[<P>The guest is absolutely against killing any civilians or innocent people be it Muslim or non Muslim :</P>
<P dir=rtl align=right><STRONG>"... لا يختلف يعني إنسان مع آخر على انه <FONT color=#0000ff>قتل الأبرياء والمدنيين</FONT> دون مبرر ولا ذنب, هذا <FONT color=#0000ff>شيء مرفوض</FONT> سواء كان الإنسان هذا مسلم أو غير مسلم..."</STRONG></P>
<P><EM>"...No one can disagree that <FONT color=#0000ff>killing innocent people and civilians</FONT> without justification or cause is <FONT color=#0000ff>rejected</FONT> by Muslims and non-Muslims..." </EM></P>
<UL>
<LI>The guest is using&nbsp; <STRONG>يعني</STRONG> , which is a gap filler commonly used in unprepared spontaneous Arabic speech. 
<LI>The noun&nbsp; <STRONG>الأبرياء</STRONG>&nbsp; is the plural form of the noun <STRONG>بريء</STRONG> <EM>(innocent).</EM> This noun is also related to the two nouns <STRONG>براءة</STRONG>&nbsp; <EM>(innocence),</EM> and to <STRONG>تبرئة</STRONG>&nbsp; <EM>(acquittal/clearance)</EM> as in the phrase<STRONG>&nbsp; تبرئة أمنية</STRONG>&nbsp; <EM>(security clearance)</EM> 
<LI>The phrase <STRONG>دون مبرر</STRONG>&nbsp; is composed of the preposition<STRONG>&nbsp; دون</STRONG><EM>&nbsp; (without)</EM> and of the noun <STRONG>مُبرر</STRONG>&nbsp; <EM>(proof/evidence/justification)</EM>. This latter noun is derived from the verb<STRONG> برّر</STRONG>&nbsp; (<EM>to justify</EM>) and to the past participle<STRONG> مُبرَّر</STRONG> <EM>(justified)</EM> as in<STRONG> غياب غير مُبرر</STRONG><EM> (unjustified</EM> <EM>absence)</EM></LI></UL>
<P><STRONG><U>Discourse Note:</U></STRONG></P>
<UL>
<LI>Note that the guest starts here with the phrase<STRONG>&nbsp; لايختلف</STRONG> <EM>(no one disagrees)</EM>, which predicts that he may say another idea that refutes the opposite. For example, one can say <STRONG>لا أحد يختلف على أن العيش في كاليفورنيا رائع ، لكن سعر البيوت غال جداً</STRONG>&nbsp; <EM>(no one disagrees that living in California is wonderful, but the house prices is so high)</EM>. </LI></UL>
<P><EM></EM></P>]]></FB><WRONG_FB><![CDATA[ad_sec209_activity_2_part1_feed.mp3]]></WRONG_FB><STIMULUS dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[]]></STIMULUS><AUD_STIMULUS><![CDATA[ad_sec209_activity_2_part2.mp3]]></AUD_STIMULUS><RESPONSE dir="ltr" esbox="0" segNo="1"><![CDATA[<P dir=rtl align=right><FONT size=2><STRONG>لماذا ذكر ضيف البرنامج فلسطين، أفغانستان و العراق؟</STRONG> </FONT>
<P dir=ltr align=left><EM><FONT size=2>Why does the guest mention Palestine, Afghanistan, and Iraq?</FONT> </EM></P>]]></RESPONSE><FB dir="ltr" esbox="1" segNo="1"><![CDATA[<P>In this part, the guest mentions Palestine, Afghanistan, and Iraq to give an example of other types of terrorism, besides car bombing:&nbsp;&nbsp; </P>
<P dir=rtl align=right><STRONG>"...إذا كان تفجير سفارة أو مدمرة أو <FONT color=#0000ff>سيارة مفخخة</FONT> ا سمه تطرف, إرهاب, تعصب, <FONT color=#0000ff>فماذا نسمي احتلال بلاد بأكملها؟</FONT> فلسطين محتلة, العراق محتل, أفغانستان محتلة والقصف والتدمير يومي في هذه البلاد</STRONG>..." </P>
<P><EM>"...if blowing up a car, destroying, or <FONT color=#0000ff>booby trapping a car</FONT> is called extremism, terrorism, and bigotry, then <FONT color=#0000ff>what do we call the occupation of an entire country?</FONT> Palestine is occupied, Iraq is occupied, Afghanistan is occupied, and bombing and destruction occur on a daily basis in this [Iraq] country..."</EM></P>
<UL>
<LI>From his tone and pace of speech one can tell that the guest is angry, and as an Iraqi he takes the program as a platform to express his thinking and belief. First he is wondering whether occupying a free country <STRONG>(احتلال بلاد بأكملها)</STRONG> would also be considered as terrorism <STRONG>ارهاب</STRONG>&nbsp; or as bigotry&nbsp; <STRONG>تعصُّب</STRONG> .&nbsp;&nbsp; </LI></UL>
<P><STRONG><U>Discourse Note:</U></STRONG></P>
<P>Another technique&nbsp; that the guest is using to carry his idea is starting with a conditional phrase, starting with<STRONG>&nbsp; اذا كان تفجير</STRONG> and ending it with <STRONG>فماذا نُسمي..... </STRONG>In Arabic, using these types of condition phrases serve to reinforce and enhance an idea or an opinion.&nbsp;&nbsp; </P>]]></FB><WRONG_FB><![CDATA[ad_sec209_activity_2_part2_feed.mp3]]></WRONG_FB><STIMULUS dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[]]></STIMULUS><AUD_STIMULUS><![CDATA[ad_sec209_activity_2_part3.mp3]]></AUD_STIMULUS><RESPONSE dir="ltr" esbox="0" segNo="2"><![CDATA[<P align=right><STRONG dir=rtl><FONT size=2>حسب ضيف البرنامج، لماذا يلجأ البعض للتطرف؟ </FONT></STRONG></P>
<P dir=ltr align=left><EM><FONT size=2>According to the program's guest, why do some people resort to extremism? </FONT></EM></P>]]></RESPONSE><FB dir="ltr" esbox="1" segNo="2"><![CDATA[<P>The guest points out that some people reluctantly resort to terrorism and extremism, because of personal motives. According to him, there are people that join the "clan of terrorism" just because one of their relatives was detained by the occupying forces. The guest here is stressing that government terrorism is more imminent&nbsp; and serious than these individuals' one.</P>
<P></P>
<P dir=rtl align=right><STRONG>"...لماذا نلوم أشخاص يعني ل..لسبب أو لآخر <FONT color=#0000ff>تطرفوا بسبب اعتقال إما والده أو أخوه أو أخته</FONT>..."&nbsp;&nbsp; </STRONG></P>
<P dir=ltr align=left><EM>"...why do we blame people, who for one reason or another<FONT color=#0000ff> resorted to extremism due to the detention of their father, brother, sister</FONT>..."</EM></P>
<UL dir=ltr>
<LI>
<DIV align=left>As you listen to the guest's comment, you will notice that he is fumbling for the&nbsp; correct words to carry his message. He used the preposition<STRONG> ل</STRONG>&nbsp; twice in the phrase<STRONG>&nbsp; ل...لسبب </STRONG></DIV>
<LI>
<DIV align=left>The construction<STRONG> إمّا....أو...أو</STRONG>&nbsp; means <EM>(either...or...or) </EM>as in the following example: <STRONG>سأسافر إما إلى أوروبا أو أمريكا أو آسيا</STRONG>&nbsp; <EM>(I will travel either to Europe, or to America, or to Asia)</EM></DIV></LI></UL>]]></FB><WRONG_FB><![CDATA[ad_sec209_activity_2_part3_feed.mp3]]></WRONG_FB><AUD_QUESTION><![CDATA[ad_sec209_activity_2.mp3]]></AUD_QUESTION><PREP_AUD><![CDATA[SELECT]]></PREP_AUD></QREC><QREC on="1"><A_Type><![CDATA[LMC]]></A_Type><UPDATED><![CDATA[Jul 19]]></UPDATED><DEV_COMMENT dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[OK]]></DEV_COMMENT><ACTY_DESCRIPTION dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[Identify new information on Islam's relation to the West that the interviewee adds to the topic.]]></ACTY_DESCRIPTION><POP_UP dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[<P align=right><STRONG><U dir=rtl>مُلاحظة:</U></STRONG></P>
<P dir=rtl align=right>في بعض القنوات الإخبارية العربية ، يدعو مقدمو البرنامج أشخاصاً مشهورين من عالم السياسة و لهم آراء قوية حول بعض المواضيع.عادة مذيع البرنامج يستأنف حلقته عن طريق طرح الأسئلة الصعبة والمثيرة ، و يترك ضيفه عادة يخوض في التعليقات الطويلة الصاخبة تفصيلا. عندما يشعرالمذيع بأن ضيفه قد ذهب أبعد في النقاش، يلجأ لتهدئة المناقشة عن طريق طرح سؤال حسّاس التي قد ليُغير مزاج الضيف. في بهذه التقنية ، تستهدف المذيع جميع انواع الجماهير : أولئك الذين يتفقون مع الضيف، وأولئك الذين لا يفعلون ذلك. وبالمثل ، في هذا النشاط، يحاول المذيع تبديل اتجاه حديث ضيفه في الوقت نفسه يحاول تقديم أسلوب و مزاج محايدين لبرنامجه. تذكر أن الضيف في التعليق الماضي زعم أن معظم الناس يصبحوا متطرفين بسبب اعتقال بعض أقاربهم. لذا، دعونا نرى ماذا رأي المذيع من هذه الفكرة؟ </P>
<P dir=ltr align=left>You can click <A onclick='window.open("html/translation.html", "", "menubar=1,scrollbars=1,resizable=1,height=400,width=500")' href="javascript:void(0);" _href="javascript:void(0);" address="html/translation.html" _onclick='window.open("html/translation.html", "", "menubar=1,scrollbars=1,resizable=1,height=400,width=500")'>here </A>to read the translation of the note above.</P>]]></POP_UP><NOTE dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[<IMG border=0 hspace=3 alt="شرطي أمام مسجد فرنسي" vspace=3 align=left src="Images/ad_sec208_islam3.gif" _src="Images/ad_sec208_islam3.gif">In this part of the conversation, the anchor interrupts his guest and diverts the conversation to another angle. Here, you will listen to both the anchor's question and his guest's comment on it. So, let us see what this part is about?]]></NOTE><FL_INST dir="rtl" esbox="0"><![CDATA[<P>اقرأ <STRONG>ملحوظة المعلم </STRONG><IMG border=0 hspace=0 alt="" align=baseline src="Images/teacherBtnSmall.gif" _src="Images/teacherBtnSmall.gif"> أولاً</P>
<P>استمع جيداً لملاحظة مُضيف البرنامج و تعليق ضيفه ثم أجب على كل سؤال يلي .&nbsp; هناك أربع صفحات في هذا النشاط.</P>]]></FL_INST><XL_INST dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[<P>Read<STRONG> </STRONG>the<STRONG> Teacher's Note</STRONG> <IMG border=0 hspace=0 alt="" align=baseline src="Images/teacherBtnSmall.gif" _src="Images/teacherBtnSmall.gif"> first.</P>
<P>Listen carefully to the anchor's observation on the topic as well as his guest's response to it and then answer each question that follows. There are four pages in this activity.</P>]]></XL_INST><PREP_TEXT dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[]]></PREP_TEXT><QText dir="rtl" esbox="0"><![CDATA[<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>المذيع</FONT></STRONG>: ليس كل هؤلاء يعني يمكن أن نقول عنهم أنهم يعنوا, يعني ان نضفي عليهم صبغة البراءة لا بد أن هناك عوامل </P>
<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>الضيف:</FONT></STRONG> اكيد اكيد نعم نعم.. نعم, أكمل عفواً</P>
<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>المذيع:</FONT></STRONG> وبالتالي المجهود ربما يجب أن يُبذل في المعسكر الإسلامي.</P>
<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>الضيف:</FONT></STRONG> صحيح. كلامك صحيح يا أخي لو كان المعسكر الإسلامي معسكر متوحد في وجهة النظر على الأقل, الآن اغلب المعسكر الإسلامي وخصوصا (الرسمي), يسير في اتجاه التيار المعادي للإسلام يعني يدين فقط هذه الأشياء الجزئيات البسيطة ولا يتكلم أي شيء عن المعاني الأخرى للإسلام. </P>]]></QText><STIMULUS dir="rtl" esbox="0"><![CDATA[<P>ما هي الملاحظة التي قدمها ضيف البرنامج لضيفه؟ </P>
<P dir=ltr align=left><EM><FONT size=2>What observation has the anchor made to his guest?</FONT></EM></P>]]></STIMULUS><AID dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[Note that in this part, the anchor interrupted his guest to ask him a question related to the concept of <STRONG>براءة</STRONG> and <STRONG>تطرف</STRONG>]]></AID><RESPONSE dir="rtl" esbox="0" itemNo="0" crrt="true"><![CDATA[معظم المتطرفين ليسوا أبرياء]]></RESPONSE><FB dir="ltr" itemNo="0" esbox="1"><![CDATA[<P><FONT color=#0000ff>Correct choice!</FONT> </P>
<P>The observation that the anchor made is that<STRONG> معظم المتطرفين ليسوا أبرياء</STRONG>&nbsp; <EM>(Most of the extremists are not innocent.)</EM></P>
<P>The anchor is trying to clarify to his guest as well as to his audience that there are some other factors behind becoming an extremist. </P>It illustrates the person as a fabric that is painted with a particular color… 
<P><EM></EM></P>
<P dir=rtl align=right><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>المذيع:</FONT> ليس كل هؤلاء يعني يمكن أن نقول عنهم أنهم يعنوا, يعني ان نضفي عليهم صبغة البراءة لا بد أن هناك عوامل</STRONG> </P>
<P><EM><FONT color=#0000ff><STRONG>Anchor:</STRONG></FONT> We cannot say that all those, we cannot say they are all innocent; there must be factors</EM> </P>
<P>The expression <STRONG>نضفي عليهم صبغة</STRONG>&nbsp; is a collocation composed of the verb<STRONG> نُضفي</STRONG>&nbsp; <EM>(we add)</EM>, the prepositional phrase<STRONG> عليهم</STRONG>&nbsp; <EM>(on them)</EM> and the noun <STRONG>صبغة</STRONG> <EM>(natural tincture).</EM> It is also a metaphor that illustrates the person as a fabric that is painted with a particular color. In our context<STRONG> البراءة</STRONG>&nbsp; <EM>(innocence)</EM> follows the noun<STRONG>صبغة </STRONG><EM>(nature)</EM> so literally the whole phrase can be translated as: <EM>(we add to them the nature/description of innocence).</EM> </P>
<P>Below are some phrases using this collocation:</P>
<UL>
<LI><STRONG>أضفى المخرج صبغة الرعب في فلمه الجديد</STRONG> <EM><FONT size=2>(the director provided a tincture of horror in his new film)</FONT></EM> 
<LI><STRONG>أضفت الكاتبة صبغة الرومانسية في كتاباتها</STRONG> <EM><FONT size=2>(the writer provided a romantic style in her writings)</FONT></EM></LI></UL>]]></FB><AUD_FB itemNo="0"><![CDATA[ad_sec209_activity_3 _feed1.mp3]]></AUD_FB><RESPONSE dir="rtl" itemNo="0" esbox="0"><![CDATA[معظم الأنظمة تُمارس الإرهاب]]></RESPONSE><FB dir="ltr" itemNo="0" esbox="0"><![CDATA[<P><FONT color=#ff0000>Incorrect choice!</FONT> </P>
<P>Actually, the anchor does not talk about any state terrorism <STRONG>ارهاب دولة</STRONG> . Listen carefully again focusing on the noun&nbsp; <STRONG>البراءة </STRONG></P>]]></FB><AUD_FB itemNo="0"><![CDATA[SELECT]]></AUD_FB><STIMULUS dir="rtl" esbox="0"><![CDATA[<P>أين يرى المذيع الحل في تحسين صورة الإسلام؟ </P>
<P dir=ltr align=left><EM><FONT size=2>What solution does the anchor suggest to improve the image of Islam?</FONT></EM></P>]]></STIMULUS><AID dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[The anchor is making a suggestion to his guest on ways to improve Islam image in the West. Focus on the term معسكر]]></AID><RESPONSE dir="rtl" itemNo="1" esbox="0"><![CDATA[يجب بذل جهد في الدول الغربية لتحسين صورة الاسلام]]></RESPONSE><FB dir="ltr" itemNo="1" esbox="0"><![CDATA[<P><FONT color=#ff0000>Incorrect choice!</FONT> </P>
<P>Actually, the anchor does not believe that efforts in Western countries should be done to improve the image of Islam. Listen carefully to the part stating with <STRONG>المجهود</STRONG>...</P>]]></FB><AUD_FB itemNo="1"><![CDATA[SELECT]]></AUD_FB><RESPONSE dir="rtl" esbox="0" itemNo="1" crrt="true"><![CDATA[يجب بذل جهد داخل المجتمع الاسلامي نفسه لتحسين صورة الاسلام]]></RESPONSE><FB dir="ltr" itemNo="1" esbox="1"><![CDATA[<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>Correct choice!</FONT></STRONG> </P>
<P>The anchor thinks that improving the image of Islam lies on the Islamic camp itself:</P>
<P></P>
<P dir=rtl align=right><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>المذيع:</FONT> وبالتالي المجهود ربما يجب أن يُبذل في المعسكر الإسلامي. </STRONG></P>
<P><EM><FONT color=#0000ff><STRONG>Anchor:</STRONG></FONT> </EM>Therefore, the effort should probably <EM>be exerted in an Islamic camp.</EM> </P>
<UL>
<LI>The phrase<STRONG> المُعسكر الإسلامي</STRONG>&nbsp; is composed of the noun&nbsp; ا<STRONG>لمُعسكر</STRONG> <EM>(camp)</EM> and of the adjective<STRONG>&nbsp; الإسلامي</STRONG>&nbsp; <EM>(Islamic).</EM> The noun<STRONG> المعسكر</STRONG>&nbsp; is related to the term&nbsp; <STRONG>عسكري</STRONG>&nbsp; <EM>(military).</EM> This latter can be either used as a noun as in <STRONG>عسكري في الجيش</STRONG>&nbsp; <EM>(a soldier in the military). </EM>It can also be used as an adjective as in<STRONG> خدمة عسكرية</STRONG>&nbsp; <EM>(military service).</EM></LI></UL>]]></FB><AUD_FB itemNo="1"><![CDATA[ad_sec209_activity_3 _feed2.mp3]]></AUD_FB><STIMULUS dir="rtl" esbox="0"><![CDATA[<P>&nbsp; ما هي العبارة التي استعملها ضيف البرنامج للتعبير عن موافقته مع&nbsp; ملاحظة المُذيع؟</P>
<P align=left><EM><FONT dir=ltr size=2>&nbsp; What phrase has the guest used to express his agreement with the host on the observation? </FONT></EM></P>]]></STIMULUS><AID dir="ltr" esbox="1"><![CDATA[<P>Here, you need to focus on a phrase usually used to address someone in a friendly way.</P>]]></AID><RESPONSE dir="rtl" itemNo="2" esbox="0"><![CDATA[نعم..أكمل عفواً]]></RESPONSE><FB dir="ltr" itemNo="2" esbox="1"><![CDATA[<P><FONT color=#ff0000>Incorrect choice!</FONT> </P>
<P>The phrase<STRONG>&nbsp; أكمل ...عفواً</STRONG>&nbsp; is actually used by the guest to ask his host to talk.&nbsp; Listen carefully focusing on the noun <STRONG>أخي </STRONG></P>]]></FB><AUD_FB itemNo="2"><![CDATA[SELECT]]></AUD_FB><RESPONSE dir="rtl" esbox="0" itemNo="2" crrt="true"><![CDATA[صحيح. كلامك صحيح يا أخي]]></RESPONSE><FB dir="ltr" itemNo="2" esbox="1"><![CDATA[<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>Correct choice!</FONT></STRONG> </P>
<P>The guest agrees with the anchor's suggestion that improving Islam's image should start from the Islamic camp first:</P>
<P></P>
<P dir=rtl align=right><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>الضيف:</FONT> صحيح. كلامك صحيح يا أخي لو كان المعسكر الإسلامي معسكر <FONT color=#0000ff>متوحد</FONT> في وجهة النظر على الأقل, </STRONG></P>
<P><EM><FONT color=#0000ff><STRONG>Guest:</STRONG></FONT> True. What you are saying is true, my brother. If the Islamic camp was a <FONT color=#0000ff>unified</FONT> camp in its point of view at least.</EM> </P>
<P>The term <STRONG>مُتوحد</STRONG>&nbsp; <EM>(unified)</EM> is derived from measure V verb<STRONG>&nbsp; توحَّد</STRONG> <EM>(to be united),</EM> and this term is related to<STRONG> الوحدة</STRONG>&nbsp; <EM>(unity)</EM> and to <STRONG>التوحد</STRONG>&nbsp; <EM>(uniting) </EM></P>
<P><STRONG><U>Cultural Note:</U></STRONG></P>
<UL>
<LI>Note that the guest here calls the anchor <STRONG>يا أخي</STRONG>&nbsp; <EM>(my brother).</EM> Pragmatically, the use of these titles in a radio or a TV news program tends to have a double role. The first is to try to connect with the anchor, especially when sharing the same idea. The second, is when one is frustrated and is trying desperately to convince&nbsp; his host about a certain point in discussion. 
<LI>Some other terms such as&nbsp; <STRONG>عزيزي</STRONG>&nbsp; <EM>(dear)</EM>&nbsp; or&nbsp; <STRONG>عزيزتي</STRONG>&nbsp; can also be used. 
<LI>In some rare situation, some guests use the name of the host as in <STRONG>يا أحمد...يا جُمانة... </STRONG>etc. Again, as I said earlier the use of these titles are not used at random, but has a pragmatic function, which is to establish a closer contact with the host, especially in a case of disagreement.</LI></UL>]]></FB><AUD_FB itemNo="2"><![CDATA[ad_sec209_activity_3 _feed3.mp3]]></AUD_FB><STIMULUS dir="rtl" esbox="0"><![CDATA[<P>كيف يصف ضيف البرنامج المعسكر الاسلامي الحالي؟ </P>
<P dir=ltr align=left><EM><FONT size=2>How does the guest describe the actual situation of the Islamic camp?</FONT></EM></P>]]></STIMULUS><AID dir="ltr" esbox="1"><![CDATA[Here, you need to focus on the guest's opinion regarding the Islamic camp. Listen carefully to the part starting with <STRONG>المُعسكر</STRONG>]]></AID><RESPONSE dir="rtl" esbox="0" itemNo="3" crrt="true"><![CDATA[يسير المعسكر الاسلامي في الاتجاه المعاكس و المُعادي للإسلام.]]></RESPONSE><FB dir="ltr" itemNo="3" esbox="0"><![CDATA[<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>Correct choice!</FONT></STRONG> </P>
<P>The guest believes that the Islamic camp is heading towards the direction of anti-Islam:</P>
<P></P>
<P dir=rtl align=right><STRONG>"...الآن اغلب المعسكر الإسلامي وخصوصا (الرسمي), يسير في <FONT color=#0000ff>اتجاه التيار المعادي للإسلام</FONT>..."</STRONG>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </P>
<P dir=ltr align=left><EM>"...Nowadays, most of the Islamic camp, especially the (official), is <FONT color=#0000ff>going in the direction of anti-Islam.</FONT>.."</EM></P>
<P align=left>The term&nbsp; <STRONG>التيار</STRONG>&nbsp; <EM>(current/trend)</EM> in this context means <EM>(direction)</EM>. The term can also be present in the following collocations:</P>
<UL>
<LI>
<DIV align=left><STRONG>التيار الكهربائي</STRONG>&nbsp; <EM>(electric current)</EM></DIV>
<LI>
<DIV align=left><STRONG>التيار السلفي</STRONG>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <EM>(the Salafi current/trend)</EM></DIV>
<LI>
<DIV align=left><STRONG>التيار المُعاكس</STRONG>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <EM>(The opposite direction)</EM></DIV></LI></UL>]]></FB><AUD_FB itemNo="3"><![CDATA[ad_sec209_activity_3 _feed4.mp3]]></AUD_FB><RESPONSE dir="rtl" itemNo="3" esbox="0"><![CDATA[المعسكر الاسلامي يعمل جاهداً لتحسين صورة الاسلام في الغرب]]></RESPONSE><FB dir="ltr" itemNo="3" esbox="0"><![CDATA[<P><FONT color=#ff0000>Incorrect choice!</FONT> </P>
<P>The guest does not think that the Islamic camp is sincerely making efforts to improve the image of Islam. You should focus on the part starting with&nbsp; <STRONG>تسير </STRONG></P>]]></FB><AUD_FB itemNo="3"><![CDATA[SELECT]]></AUD_FB><AUD_STIMULUS itemNo=""><![CDATA[ad_sec209_activity_3.mp3]]></AUD_STIMULUS><AUD_STIMULUS itemNo=""><![CDATA[SELECT]]></AUD_STIMULUS><PREP_AUD itemNo=""><![CDATA[SELECT]]></PREP_AUD></QREC><QREC on="1"><A_Type><![CDATA[LPT]]></A_Type><UPDATED><![CDATA[Jul 19]]></UPDATED><DEV_COMMENT dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[OK]]></DEV_COMMENT><ACTY_DESCRIPTION dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[Analyze the relevance of the linguistic elements to the meaning of the discussion.]]></ACTY_DESCRIPTION><POP_UP dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[]]></POP_UP><NOTE dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[]]></NOTE><FL_INST dir="rtl" esbox="0"><![CDATA[<P><STRONG>استمع إلى المقطع المسجل بأكمله و بعد ذلك قم بالضغط ،&nbsp; ثم اكمل الفراغات في الجمل التالية بالعربية ، تستطيع ايضاً الاستماع إلى الكلمة المطلوبة لكل فراغ. </STRONG></P>
<P><STRONG>بعد الانتهاء من تعبئة الفراغ اضغط على <IMG border=0 hspace=0 alt="" align=baseline src="Images/btnViewTranscript.gif" _src="Images/btnViewTranscript.gif"> للتاكد من إجابتك.</STRONG> </P>
<P></P>
<P><STRONG></STRONG></P>
<P></P>]]></FL_INST><XL_INST dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[<P>Listen to the entire audio, and then fill in the blanks with the missing words in Arabic. </P>
<P>Then click on <IMG border=0 hspace=0 alt="" align=baseline src="Images/btnViewTranscript.gif" _src="Images/btnViewTranscript.gif"> for an explanation of the answer. </P>]]></XL_INST><PREP_TEXT dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[]]></PREP_TEXT><QText dir="rtl" esbox="0"><![CDATA[أصبحت الصورة التي تُقدم عن الإسلام هي مجموعة أشخاص أو أفراد فين في العراق و في أفغانستان وكأنه هذا هو صار الإسلام. هذا ليس صحيح. ال ال.. المسؤول عن<U><STRONG> تصحيح صورة الإسلام</STRONG></U> هي الجهات الإعلامية الرسمية وليس الأفراد وليست المنظمات التي <U><STRONG>لا حول لها ولا قوة</STRONG></U>. لم يستطع الآن أن يظهر في الإعلام, كما يُمجِد حاكم أو يُمجِد فعل معين أو يُمجِد انجاز أن يُمجِد يعني تاريخ الإسلام في الأندلس أو تاريخ الإسلام في فلسطين أو تاريخ الإسلام في الهند وفي آسيا. لا احد يستطيع. المسؤولية ليست مسؤوليتي أنا كشخص, أنا ممكن اعمل مع اللي بجواري لكن كم يكن كثير <STRONG><U>مقابل إعلام دولة كاملة</U></STRONG> أو إعلام عدة دول. فالمسؤولية الصحيح لكن يجب أن تتولى الدول وبإنصاف بإنصاف أن تدافع عن صورة الإسلام في الغرب حتى يعرفون الغربيين الصورة الحقيقية غير الصورة لأحداث سبتمبر <U><STRONG>وصورة السيارات المفخخة</STRONG></U> هذه صورة لا تشكل يعني أي شيء من الإسلام.]]></QText><STIMULUS dir="ltr" esbox="1"><![CDATA[The missing part is composed of&nbsp; three-word Idafa, and it is related to the image of Islam.]]></STIMULUS><FB dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[<P>This is the missing part: <STRONG>تصحيح صورة الإسلام</STRONG> <EM>(improving the image of Islam)</EM></P>
<UL>
<LI>The term <STRONG>تصحيح</STRONG> is the verbal noun derived from measure II&nbsp; <STRONG>صحَّح</STRONG>&nbsp; <EM>(to correct/improve)</EM> 
<LI>Note as in English, the term <STRONG>صورة</STRONG>&nbsp; <EM>(image) </EM>can be used both literally and metaphorically.</LI></UL>
<P></P>]]></FB><AID><![CDATA[transcription_1.mp3]]></AID><STIMULUS dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[This is a religious idiom used by Muslims to denote human weaknesses before God's ultimate power .]]></STIMULUS><FB dir="ltr" esbox="1"><![CDATA[<P>This is the missing part: <STRONG>لا حول لها و لا قوة</STRONG> <EM>(powerless)</EM> </P>
<P>However, the phrase <STRONG>لا حول له و لا قوة</STRONG>&nbsp; can be literally translated as <EM>it has no strength nor power</EM>. Note that <EM>it</EM> or the pronoun&nbsp; <STRONG>ها </STRONG>here refers to the individual and NGO's, that, according to the guest, are powerless, to improve the Islam image.</P>
<P><STRONG><U>Socio-Cultural Note:</U></STRONG></P>
<P>The phrase&nbsp; <STRONG>لاحول و لاقوة إلا بالله</STRONG> , which can be literally translated as: <EM>There is power or force only from God,</EM> is commonly used among Muslims when hearing a bad news or when someone is irritated and is trying to control his temper. For example: </P>
<P dir=rtl align=right><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>يوسف:</FONT> يا أحمد هل تعلم أن الحاج كريم مريض بسرطان الرئة </STRONG></P>
<P dir=rtl align=right><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>أحمد:</FONT> <FONT color=#003366><U>لا حول و لا قوة إلا بالله </U></FONT></STRONG></P>
<P dir=ltr align=left><EM><FONT color=#0000ff><STRONG>Youssef:</STRONG></FONT> Ahmad , do you know that Haj Karim is suffering from lung cancer?</EM></P>
<P dir=ltr align=left><EM><FONT color=#0000ff><STRONG>Ahmad:</STRONG></FONT> <U>Oh! My goodness! </U></EM></P>
<P></P>]]></FB><AID><![CDATA[transcription_2.mp3]]></AID><STIMULUS dir="ltr" esbox="1"><![CDATA[The missing part is composed of four words related to media.]]></STIMULUS><FB dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[<P>This is the missing part: <STRONG>مُقابل اعلام دولة كاملة </STRONG><EM>(compared to the media of whole state)</EM></P>
<UL>
<LI>Here, the guest is pointing out that NGO's and individuals are powerless vis a vis the media of an entire nation in bringing a positive attitude towards Islam in Europe.</LI></UL>]]></FB><AID><![CDATA[transcription_3.mp3]]></AID><STIMULUS dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[The missing part is composed of three words: an Idafa and an adjective. This phrase is related to a consequence of a terrorist act.]]></STIMULUS><FB dir="ltr" esbox="1"><![CDATA[<P>This is the missing part: <STRONG>صورة السيارات المفخخة </STRONG><EM>(car bombing images)</EM></P>
<UL>
<LI>The past participle<STRONG>&nbsp; المُفخَّخة</STRONG>&nbsp; is derived from the measure II verb <STRONG>فخَّخ</STRONG> <EM>(to rig)</EM> and the term is also related to the noun<STRONG>&nbsp; فَخّ</STRONG> <EM>(trap) </EM>
<LI><STRONG>سيارة مُفخخة</STRONG> <EM>(car bomb)</EM> is a term that has existed for decades to refer to any terrorist activity involving a car explosion. 
<LI>After September 11, the phrase <STRONG>سيارة مُفخخة</STRONG>&nbsp; has been primarily attributed to the Middle East. </LI></UL>]]></FB><AID><![CDATA[transcription_4.mp3]]></AID><AUD_STIMULUS><![CDATA[ad_sec209_partial_transcription.mp3]]></AUD_STIMULUS><AUD_STIMULUS><![CDATA[SELECT]]></AUD_STIMULUS><PREP_AUD><![CDATA[SELECT]]></PREP_AUD></QREC><QREC on="1"><A_Type><![CDATA[LMF]]></A_Type><UPDATED><![CDATA[Jul 19]]></UPDATED><DEV_COMMENT dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[OK]]></DEV_COMMENT><ACTY_DESCRIPTION dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[Evaluate your understanding of the question/answer relationship based on the interview.]]></ACTY_DESCRIPTION><POP_UP dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[]]></POP_UP><NOTE dir="ltr" esbox="1"><![CDATA[You now have a broad and a detailed knowledge about the content and details of the lesson (Part 1 &amp; 2). This activity, will help you sum up all the core ideas presented in the whole program interview. You can click on <STRONG>Primary Audio</STRONG> to listen to the entire conversation, and you can also go to <STRONG>View Transcript</STRONG> to read the transcript while listening if you meet any difficulties.]]></NOTE><FL_INST dir="rtl" esbox="0"><![CDATA[<P dir=rtl align=right>استمع الى الحوار الاخباري مرة اخرى لتراجع مدى استيعابك للدرس، باستطاعتك الضعط&nbsp; على "View Transcript" ايضاً اثناء الاستماع إلى التسجيل. </P>
<P dir=rtl align=right>استمع الى المقاطع الصوتية و التي تحتوي على سؤال ثم اختر الاجابة الصحيحة من الناحية اليسرى. </P>]]></FL_INST><XL_INST dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[<P>Listen to the <STRONG>Primary Audio</STRONG> again to refresh your comprehension. Click on <STRONG>View Transcript</STRONG> and read the transcript as you listen. For each segment, listen to an audio clip that contains a question. Click <STRONG>Select </STRONG>and then click on the correct answer for the question in the opposite column.</P>You can review the transcript if needed and then listen to the questions on the right to match them with the appropriate answers.]]></XL_INST><PREP_TEXT dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[]]></PREP_TEXT><SRC_TYPE><![CDATA[audio]]></SRC_TYPE><SRC_TEXT dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[]]></SRC_TEXT><SRC_TEXT dir="rtl" esbox="0"><![CDATA[<STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>المذيع:</FONT></STRONG>&nbsp; دراسةٍ أعدها معهد العلاقات الدولية الألماني على عينة من الأوروبيين تمثل مختلف الشرائح الاجتماعية, طٌرح محور هذه الدراسة وهو تساؤل مفاده ماذا يخطر ببالك عندما تسمع كلمة إسلام؟ الإجابات كانت أن الصورة التي يحملها أغلب الأوروبيين عن المجتمعات الإسلامية سلبية إلى حدٍ كبير. نحو ثلاثة أرباع المشاركين في الدراسة ردّوا بأن الإسلام يعني بالنسبة لهم قمع المرأة والتطرف والإرهاب. ولم يقدم إلا نحو ربع المشاركين إجابات تعكس رؤيةً أفضل للديانة الإسلامية. كما أوضح باحثون أوروبيون وعرب شاركوا في ندوة نُظِمت على هامش معرض فرانكفورت الدولي للكتاب لبحث هذا الموضوع, أوضحوا أن ثمة نظرة سطحية شائعة عن الإسلام في أوروبا وفي الغرب عامة لا تشتمل على الجوانب الحضارية والإنسانية الكثيرة التي يزخر بها الإسلام 
<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>المذيع:</FONT></STRONG> . نتحول الآن إلى المستمع رافع سعيد الذي يهاتفنا من الرمادي في العراق, سيد رافع يا أهلا بك.</P>
<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>الضيف:</FONT></STRONG> أهلا وسهلاً بك. </P>
<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>المذيع:</FONT></STRONG> رافع ما رأيك في هذه النظرة السائدة النظرة السلبية التي خلصت إليها هذه الدراسة والتي تظهر في وسائل الإعلام الغربية أحيانا أو كثيراً, ما رأيك فيها وما الذي يمكن لل.. للإسلام وللمجتمع الإسلامي أن يعمل لأجل تغيير هذه النظرة؟ </P>
<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>الضيف:</FONT></STRONG> نعم شكراً جزيلاً, أولا أهنئكم بمناسبة شهر رمضان الكريم وأقول لكم كل عام وانتم بخير.</P>
<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>المذيع:</FONT></STRONG> وأنت بألف خير, تفضل.</P>
<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>الضيف:</FONT></STRONG> ثانياً الإسلام, لا شك هو دين الله سبحانه وتعالى الذي ختم به الأديان والرسالات. والمشكلة الآن هي ليست يعني هي قناعة الآخرين بالإسلام, المشكلة هي الصورة التي يحاول الإعلام المعادي للإسلام تشكيلها وتصوير الإسلام بها. </P>
<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>الضيف:</FONT></STRONG> لا يختلف يعني إنسان مع آخر على انه قتل الأبرياء والمدنيين دون مبرر ولا ذنب, هذا شيء مرفوض سواء كان الإنسان هذا مسلم أو غير مسلم. لكن هنا سؤالان إذا كان تفجير سفارة أو مدمرة أو سيارة مفخخة سمه تطرف, إرهاب, تعصب, فماذا نسمي احتلال بلاد بأكملها؟ فلسطين محتلة, العراق محتل, أفغانستان محتلة والقصف والتدمير يومي في هذه البلاد. ثانياً لماذا نلوم أشخاص يعني ل..لسبب أو لآخر تطرفوا بسبب اعتقال إما والده أو أخوه أو أخته ومسجنه أو كذا ولا نلوم دول وحكومات كاملة تقوم بهذه الأعمال ليل نهار تعدم وتحاكم وتسجن بسبب الاشتباه كله اشتباه ب..</P>
<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>المذيع:</FONT></STRONG> طيب سيد سيد رافع</P>
<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>الضيف:</FONT></STRONG> أو كذا, نعم</P>
<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>المذيع:</FONT></STRONG> ليس كل هؤلاء يعني يمكن أن نقول عنهم أنهم يعنوا, يعني ان نضفي عليهم صبغة البراءة لا بد أن هناك عوامل </P>
<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>الضيف:</FONT></STRONG> اكيد اكيد نعم نعم.. نعم, أكمل عفواً</P>
<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>المذيع:</FONT></STRONG> وبالتالي المجهود ربما يجب أن يُبذل في المعسكر الإسلامي.</P>
<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>الضيف:</FONT></STRONG> صحيح. كلامك صحيح يا أخي لو كان المعسكر الإسلامي معسكر متوحد في وجهة النظر على الأقل, الآن اغلب المعسكر الإسلامي وخصوصا (الرسمي), يسير في اتجاه التيار المعادي للإسلام يعني يدين فقط هذه الأشياء الجزئيات البسيطة ولا يتكلم أي شيء عن المعاني الأخرى للإسلام.</P>
<P><STRONG><FONT color=#0000ff>الضيف:</FONT></STRONG> أصبحت الصورة التي تُقدم عن الإسلام هي مجموعة أشخاص أو أفراد فين في العراق و في أفغانستان وكأنه هذا هو صار الإسلام. هذا ليس صحيح. ال ال.. المسئول عن تصحيح صورة الإسلام هي الجهات الإعلامية الرسمية وليس الأفراد وليست المنظمات التي لا حول لها ولا قوة. لم يستطع الآن أن يظهر في الإعلام, كما يُمجِد حاكم أو يُمجِد فعل معين أو يُمجِد انجاز أن يُمجِد يعني تاريخ الإسلام في الأندلس أو تاريخ الإسلام في فلسطين أو تاريخ الإسلام في الهند وفي آسيا. لا احد يستطيع. المسؤولية ليست مسؤوليتي أنا كشخص, أنا ممكن اعمل مع اللي بجواري لكن كم يكن كثير مقابل إعلام دولة كاملة أو إعلام عدة دول. فالمسؤولية الصحيح لكن يجب أن تتولى الدول وبإنصاف بإنصاف أن تدافع عن صورة الإسلام في الغرب حتى يعرفون الغربيين الصورة الحقيقية غير الصورة لأحداث سبتمبر وصورة السيارات المفخخة هذه صورة لا تشكل يعني أي شيء من الإسلام. </P>]]></SRC_TEXT><ANS><![CDATA[0]]></ANS><FB><![CDATA[1]]></FB><NUM_Q dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[7]]></NUM_Q><AID><![CDATA[3]]></AID><FB_FL dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[]]></FB_FL><RESPONSE dir="rtl" esbox="0"><![CDATA[<P align=center>يظن معظم الأوروبيين أن الاسلام يمثل قمع المرأة الارهاب و التطرف </P>]]></RESPONSE><RIGHT_FB dir="ltr" esbox="1"><![CDATA[<P><FONT color=#0000ff>Correct choice!</FONT> </P>
<P>This statement translation is: </P>
<P align=center><STRONG>يظن معظم الأوروبيين أن الاسلام يمثل قمع المرأة الارهاب و التطرف </STRONG></P>
<P align=center>Most Europeans think that Islam represent oppression of women, terrorism, and extremism.</P>
<P><STRONG><U>Context of the statement:</U></STRONG> This statement is mentioned in the lesson (Part 1), where the anchor talked about Europeans ‘ view on Islam:</P>
<P dir=rtl align=right>1-&nbsp; <STRONG>الإسلام يعني بالنسبة لهم <FONT color=#0000ff>قمع المرأة والتطرف والإرهاب </FONT></STRONG></P>
<P></P>
<P></P>]]></RIGHT_FB><WRONG_FB dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[<P><FONT color=#ff0000>Incorrect choice!</FONT> </P>
<P>This audio segment is from the lesson (Part 1). It is the result of a European survey on Islam. </P>]]></WRONG_FB><FB_FL dir="rtl" esbox="0"><![CDATA[]]></FB_FL><RESPONSE dir="rtl" esbox="0"><![CDATA[<P align=center>يُشير ضيف البرنامج أن&nbsp; الاعلام هو المسؤول عن تشويه صورة الاسلام </P>]]></RESPONSE><RIGHT_FB dir="ltr" esbox="1"><![CDATA[<P><FONT color=#0000ff>Correct choice!</FONT>&nbsp; </P>
<P>This statement translation is: </P>
<P align=center><STRONG>يُشير ضيف البرنامج أن&nbsp; الاعلام هو المسؤول عن تشويه صورة الاسلام </STRONG></P>
<P align=center><FONT size=2><EM>The program's guest indicates that the media&nbsp; is responsible for distorting the image of Islam in Europe.</EM></FONT></P>
<P align=left><STRONG><U>Context of the statement:</U></STRONG> This statement is mentioned in the lesson (Part 1), where the guest discusses the role of media in increasing anti-Islamic feelings in the West:<STRONG> الاعلام المعادي للاسلام</STRONG></P>
<P dir=rtl align=right><STRONG>2- المشكلة هي الصورة التي يحاول <FONT color=#0000ff>الإعلام المعادي للإسلام</FONT> تشكيلها وتصوير الإسلام بها </STRONG></P>]]></RIGHT_FB><WRONG_FB dir="ltr" esbox="1"><![CDATA[<P><FONT color=#ff0000>Incorrect choice!</FONT> </P>
<P>This audio segment is taken from the lesson (Part 1).&nbsp; Here the guest is blaming the media for the growing negative feelings about Islam in Europe.</P>]]></WRONG_FB><FB_FL dir="rtl" esbox="0"><![CDATA[]]></FB_FL><RESPONSE dir="rtl" esbox="0"><![CDATA[<P align=center>يعتقد ضيف البرنامج أن لبعض المتطرفين دوافع شخصية</P>]]></RESPONSE><RIGHT_FB dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[<P><FONT color=#0000ff>Correct choice!</FONT> </P>
<P>This statement translation is: </P>
<P align=center><STRONG>يعتقد ضيف البرنامج أن لبعض المتطرفين دوافع شخصية</STRONG></P>
<P align=center><EM><FONT size=2>The guest believes that some of the extremists have their own personal motives.</FONT></EM></P>
<P dir=ltr align=left><STRONG><U>Context of the statement:</U></STRONG> This statement is mentioned in the lesson (Part 2), where the guest explained that some people resort to extremism as a "vengeance" act because some of their relatives are detained by occupying forces.</P>
<P dir=rtl align=right><STRONG>3- لماذا نلوم أشخاص يعني ل..لسبب أو لآخر <FONT color=#0000ff>تطرفوا بسبب اعتقال إما والده أو أخوه</FONT> أو أخته أو كذا&nbsp; - </STRONG></P>]]></RIGHT_FB><WRONG_FB dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[<P><FONT color=#ff0000>Incorrect choice!</FONT> </P>
<P>This audio segment is taken from the lesson (Part 2). Here the guest is claiming that some extremists are innocent.</P>]]></WRONG_FB><FB_FL dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[]]></FB_FL><RESPONSE dir="rtl" esbox="0"><![CDATA[<P align=center>يؤكد مذيع البرنامج أن ليس كل المتشددين أبرياء و أن هناك عوامل أخرى </P>]]></RESPONSE><RIGHT_FB dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[<P><FONT color=#0000ff>Correct choice!</FONT> </P>
<P>This statement translation is: </P>
<P align=center><STRONG>يؤكد مذيع البرنامج أن ليس كل المتشددين أبرياء و أن هناك عوامل أخرى </STRONG></P>
<P align=center><FONT size=2><EM>The anchor confirms that not all extremists are innocent and that there are other contributing factors.</EM></FONT></P>
<P dir=ltr align=left><STRONG><U>Context of the statement:</U></STRONG> -This statement is mentioned in the lesson (Part 1), when the anchor interrupted his guest.</P>
<P dir=rtl align=right><STRONG>4- ليس كل هؤلاء يعني يمكن أن نقول عنهم أنهم يعنوا, يعني ان نضفي عليهم <FONT color=#0000ff>صبغة البراءة</FONT> لا بد أن هناك عوامل&nbsp;&nbsp; </STRONG></P>]]></RIGHT_FB><WRONG_FB dir="ltr" esbox="1"><![CDATA[<P><FONT color=#ff0000>Incorrect choice!</FONT> </P>
<P>This audio part is taken from the lesson (Part 2). Here the anchor is contradicting his guest on the term "innocent" and "extremists".</P>]]></WRONG_FB><FB_FL dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[]]></FB_FL><RESPONSE dir="rtl" esbox="0"><![CDATA[<P align=center>يتسائل المذيع عمَا اذا كان للمعسكر الاسلامي دور جاد في تصحيح صورة الاسلام في الغرب </P>]]></RESPONSE><RIGHT_FB dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[<P><FONT color=#0000ff>Correct choice!</FONT> </P>
<P>This statement translation is: </P>
<P align=center><STRONG>يسأل المذيع ضيفه عمَا اذا كان للمعسكر الاسلامي دور أجود في تصحيح صورة الاسلام في الغرب </STRONG></P>
<P align=center><EM><FONT size=2>The anchor asks his guest whether the Islamic camp could contribute better in improving the image of Islam in the West</FONT></EM>.</P>
<P align=left><STRONG><U>Context of the statement:</U></STRONG> This statement is mentioned in the lesson (Part 2), where the anchor asked his guest about the role of the Islamic camp in correcting false attitudes about Islam.</P>
<P dir=rtl align=right><STRONG>5- وبالتالي المجهود ربما يجب أن يُبذل في <FONT color=#0000ff>المعسكر الإسلامي</FONT>. </STRONG></P>]]></RIGHT_FB><WRONG_FB dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[<P><FONT color=#ff0000>Incorrect choice!</FONT> </P>
<P>This audio part is taken from&nbsp; the lesson (Part2). Here it is the anchor's question on the role of the Islamic camp to improve Islam image.</P>]]></WRONG_FB><FB_FL dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[]]></FB_FL><RESPONSE dir="rtl" esbox="0"><![CDATA[<P align=center>يعتقد ضيف البرنامج أن المعسكر الاسلامي لا يسير في الاتجاه الصحيح ليُحسِّن صورة الاسلام في الغرب. </P>]]></RESPONSE><RIGHT_FB dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[<P><FONT color=#0000ff>Correct choice!</FONT> </P>
<P>This statement translation is: </P>
<P align=center><STRONG dir=rtl>يعتقد ضيف البرنامج أن المعسكر الاسلامي لا يسير في الاتجاه الصحيح ليُحسِّن صورة الاسلام في الغرب. </STRONG></P>
<P align=center><EM><FONT size=2>The guest states that the Islamic camp is not heading on the right path towards improving the image of Islam in the West.</FONT></EM></P>
<P align=left><STRONG><U>Context of the statement:</U></STRONG> This statement is mentioned in the lesson (Part 2), where the guest criticized the Islamic camp.</P>
<P dir=rtl align=right><STRONG>6- يسير في <FONT color=#0000ff>اتجاه التيار المعادي للإسلام</FONT> يعني يدين فقط هذه الأشياء الجزئيات البسيطة ولا يتكلم أي شيء عن المعاني الأخرى للإسلام </STRONG></P>]]></RIGHT_FB><WRONG_FB dir="ltr" esbox="0"><![CDATA[<P><FONT color=#ff0000>Incorrect choice!</FONT> </P>
<P>This is the final idea that the guest mentioned in this lesson, blaming the Islamic camp as being reckless in improving the image of Islam in the West.</P>]]></WRONG_FB><SRC_AUD><![CDATA[ad_sec209_final_act.mp3]]></SRC_AUD><AUD_STIMULUS><![CDATA[ad_sec209_final1.mp3]]></AUD_STIMULUS><AUD_STIMULUS><![CDATA[ad_sec209_final2.mp3]]></AUD_STIMULUS><AUD_STIMULUS><![CDATA[ad_sec209_final3.mp3]]></AUD_STIMULUS><AUD_STIMULUS><![CDATA[ad_sec209_final4.mp3]]></AUD_STIMULUS><AUD_STIMULUS><![CDATA[ad_sec209_final5.mp3]]></AUD_STIMULUS><AUD_STIMULUS><![CDATA[ad_sec209_final6.mp3]]></AUD_STIMULUS><PREP_AUD><![CDATA[SELECT]]></PREP_AUD></QREC><QREC><A_Type><![CDATA[]]></A_Type></QREC></DB>
